<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>Graescence Chapters Feed</id>
    <title>Graescence Chapters Feed</title>
    <updated>2023-01-10T17:44:56.835Z</updated>
    <generator>Feed npm package</generator>
    <author>
        <name>apoetsanon</name>
    </author>
    <link rel="self" href="http://localhost:3000/feeds/chapters/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>RSS Feed of chapters from the Graescence Webnovel</subtitle>
    <logo>http://localhost:3000/images/profile.png</logo>
    <icon>http://localhost:3000/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2023, apotesanon</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jump]]></title>
        <id>Volume_1.c01-Stan-Jump</id>
        <link href="http://localhost:3000/chapters/Volume_1.c01-Stan-Jump"/>
        <updated>2022-12-31T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Stanley Chao stood on the edge of a flimsy wooden board over a hundred paces above the ground. Far below, patches of dirt and worn grass were revealed as featureless browns and greens from dizzying spotlights that roamed the earth below.</p>
<p>A man stood center among three fixed spotlights, himself a red blur under the intense light. He gestured gregariously, sweeping his arm in a wide circle before raising it to point at Stan. Several spotlights followed, blinding Stan from seeing anything else. The man bellowed something but his words were drowned out by the roar of a crowd.</p>
<p>Stan tied a blindfold over his eyes with slow, exaggerated motions. He raised his arms and edged forward until half his feet dangled over nothing. Before him rested a swing, its rope swaying lightly.</p>
<p>Silence descended as though on cue.</p>
<p>The swing dropped.</p>
<p>Stan tilted forward and let gravity take him. It took no effort at all to court death, just a small shift in weight.</p>
<p>A collective gasp from the crowd touched his ears before the wind tore it away. Below him, the swing gained too much momentum. It curved away from him as death's irony, the plummeting man chasing the swing only a finger out of reach.</p>
<p>Stanley Chao was a dead man. He knew it; the man on the ground knew it; the crowd knew it. With nothing but air between him and an abrupt rendezvous with death, his only hope sped away in a parabolic arc.</p>
<p>He began to flail in the air like one who'd never jumped before, his fingers grasping nothing but air.</p>
<p>Such a simple mistake to make, barely a split second off timing.</p>
<p>On a stand that mirrored his stood a woman, a true beauty wearing a tight dress of patterned red tailored to draw the eye. Yet where there should have been supreme grace and unflappable confidence, she wore a hand on her mouth and horror in her eyes. She belatedly threw her own swing down, presumably in an attempt to save the doomed man.</p>
<p>Didn't matter. Not really. Any fool could see her swing wouldn't make it in time. Several in the audience had stood as though to stop fate itself, yet there was nothing to do but revel in the horror of a stunt gone terribly wrong.</p>
<p>They'd paid to see something fantastic, after all. The poster guaranteed it, or your money back.</p>
<p>In a fluid motion, the beauty ripped off her dress, revealing a striped leotard that matched Stan's. She leapt without a pebble of hesitation. Half the audience tore their eyes off the plummeting man to watch a new tragedy unfold.</p>
<p>Despite the obvious disaster, the beauty couldn't keep a small smile from her face as she flew through the air.</p>
<p>Stan suddenly stopped flailing, and then...physics stopped making sense. The woman's swing turned glossy, reflecting more light than it should. Most didn't notice, eyes glued to either grace or tragedy. Then the woman's swing suddenly <em>sped up</em>.</p>
<p>A trick of the light, or a trick of the mind. Most couldn't understand what had happened. She'd jumped after him, and they would <em>swear</em> the swing couldn't possibly make it in time. And yet, somehow, Stanley Chao grasped the woman's swing at precisely the same moment her fingers alighted on his.</p>
<p>The crowd watch in stunned silence as the flailing man transformed into an acrobat mirroring the woman's grace. They crossed at the apex of their swing before using the momentum to double flip up onto their counterpart's platforms.</p>
<p>With a dramatic flourish, Stan ripped off his blindfold and bowed.</p>
<p>The crowd jumped up in a roar of cheers and applause in a sound would never grow old. Never. He nodded to his counterpart, and they both stepped off their platforms to begin a complicated dance of flips and tricks, all done to the roar of an approving crowd.</p>
<p>Not all thundered applause, though. Two men dressed in sharply tailored suits of black and gray had watched the affair with detached interest. They had not gasped at the falling man, nor applauded the stunt's finale. They had not watched Stan at all, nor even the women.</p>
<p>They had watched the swing.</p>
<p>As Stan and his counterpart swung flips through the air, the pair stood and began to make their way down the stands, unhurried and unconcerned, their steps as inevitable as fate itself.</p>
<hr>
<p>"Incredible!" Chi Wan clasped Stan's shoulder, squeezing. "You and Min blew it away. I swear even I thought you'd courted death's embrace."</p>
<p>Stanley smiled polite and returned to the younger man a small nod.</p>
<p>"You flatter me," Stan said with an undercurrent of, 'please stop talking'.</p>
<p>He continued walking through a narrow hallway made of waxed canvas, the younger man only a half a step behind. The patter of rain filled the brief silence as the both of them picked their way around puddles seeping in from under the folds.</p>
<p>"You know I don't. There's a performance, and then there's you two. You? You're...ah, I could only wish to be as good as you."</p>
<p>"Time and practice," Stan lied, "time and practice."</p>
<p>Oh, Stan had no doubt Chi would eventually become a great performer, but there was no substituting for Stan's gift.</p>
<p>"But it's more than that—oh I know, I know. You practice just as much—no, <em>more</em> than any of us. But you? You've got a trick, or something. I couldn't do that, just...fall like you did. That..." The boy shook his head. "That's something else."</p>
<p>Stan frowned at the boy's words but kept walking. They arrived in a spacious tent filled with a riot of color and sound where upcoming performers stretched, practiced, or simply relaxed. They passed strange animals with their trainers enticing treats for tricks, performers twisted into convoluted shapes, clowns on stilts, and ever increasing oddities.</p>
<p>He stopped at a pair of dancers, their motions syncopated and complex as they counterbalanced in twirls, revolving and flowing in a way that tempted one to think they must be dancing on air. Lead and follow became blurred as they traded off guiding one another on cues only they knew, their steps intricate, intimate.</p>
<p>A hint of longing tainted Stan's face as one woman closed her eyes, face serene and content, fully trusting her lifelong partner.</p>
<p>"You miss the point," he said distantly. "The trick is just that, a trick. It is important to grab the attention, but that is all. This," he nodded to the couple, "is true art."</p>
<p>He turned fully to the boy. "Do not pursue the trick. Pursue the art."</p>
<p>"Yes, yes, of course, I understand. I will—I <em>do</em> pursue it every day."</p>
<p>He did not. The boy practiced, certainly, but his eyes were still clouded by the glamour of too many spotlights.</p>
<p>"Before you pursue anything, though, I believe Mrs. Chen will have your hide if you're late to the walks?"</p>
<p>"The wha—oh!" The boy's eyes widened comically. He spun to leave then jerked back to Stan. "Oh uh, thank you!" He half bowed, turning it into a twisting motion as he tried to turn and run all at the same time.</p>
<p>Stan watched the boy rush back with a small smile. The smile fell off when he turned back toward the couple. He watched them for a few seconds more before it became too much. He turned from his regret and continued his way toward the back of the tent.</p>
<p>"Min Li," he said as he sat down on a stool in front of a mirror ringed by inert lights. He reached over and fed a small panel his graescence until the lights brightened enough to highlight his face. He began checking over his makeup.</p>
<p>"Stan-<em>li</em>," she replied belatedly, using a more traditional pronunciation of his name instead of the one his parent's had given him.</p>
<p>"You did well," he said, trying to infuse genuine warmth into his tone, yet his uncertainty tainted his attempt. He never could figure her out.</p>
<p>"Of course," she replied, giving him a false smile, "and you did..."</p>
<p>She cocked her head, then turned back to touch up her own makeup.</p>
<p>On stage, they were synced in a way few could attain. He could never understand why she hated him for it.</p>
<p>He stripped off his leotard, leaving him clad only in tight underwear. She mirrored him with the same practiced movements. A few moments later, they'd pulled on a different set of tights covering most of their body without adding any modesty whatsoever. Modesty was a long running joke in a troupe like this.</p>
<p>Their next performance was his favorite, a dance in the air among silks. Designed to blend in with the streamers, their costumes would serve to obscure their movements without detracting from the grace of the dance.</p>
<p>It was one of the few performances that required no tricks of him. Just beauty; just art.</p>
<p>He glanced at his unwilling partner looking for a connection, but she was staring at the mirror with a blank expression.</p>
<p>A commotion behind them drew their attention. Min Li spun on her stool, then jerked as though struck. A small gasp escaped her lips, her eyes gone wide in horror stained panic. It was, quite literally, the most emotion he'd ever seen her display.</p>
<p>He slid off his stool and with a couple steps stood beside her. A pair of men walked towards them, eyes locked on Min Li. Though they were still a ways away, he could see that they were extremely well dressed, <em>dangerously</em> well dressed, the kind of dress Stan had learned to avoid. Dark red and green silks wrapped their upper bodies, flaring into loose fitting pants that flowed around their steps. From their back fell a thick gray cloak, hoods pulled back and still shedding beads of rain.</p>
<p>But why a pair of Royals would degrade themselves to walk among a lowly troupe like this, he had no idea.</p>
<p>He turned back to Min Li and the question died on his lips. His eyes focused beyond onto yet another pair walking toward them, <em>their</em> eyes locked on him. His stomach churned acid at the sight of them, a man and women, both dressed in a perfectly tailored black suit covering gray silk beneath it. The way the black cloth seemed to shimmer beneath the light was unmistakable, as was the antiquated cut of long split-tails that wrapped their legs.</p>
<p>Inquisitors.</p>
<p>There was only one rational thing to do when a pair of Inquisitors had you in their sights.</p>
<p>"Run," he whispered.</p>
<p>Min Li started at the sound, then followed Stan's gaze toward the Inquisitors.</p>
<p>"What? Impossible. Why would they..."</p>
<p>She slowly turned to Stan, giving him a questioning look. He turned sheepish, and her expression turned deeply incredulous, which was...fair. Inquisitors generally only addressed issues that threatened the stability of the Empire and, by extension, the world itself.</p>
<p>"Min Li," he gave her a small bow, "it has been a...well, something, but I'm afraid this is where we must part."</p>
<p>He turned to run.</p>
<p>"Oh, no you don't." She grasped his forearm with startling strength.</p>
<p>"I am...um." His eyes jumped between between her and the Inquisitors as confusion mixed with a rising panic. "I don't think you quite understand the—"</p>
<p>"I understand enough. You will take me with you."</p>
<p>"<em>What?</em>" Only the suicidal would come within striking distance of Inquisitors.</p>
<p>"Was I not clear? I'm coming. Now," she glanced at the pair of Royals approaching, "what is your plan of escape?"</p>
<p>"My plan of <em>what</em>!?"</p>
<p>"Your..." her face tightened, "surely you have a plan."</p>
<p>He snorted. "Yeah, sure. I'll just—oh, too late. She's gonna jump."</p>
<p>The female Inquisitor drew a wooden knife from her jacket. Experience had taught him that once they drew their knives, it was usually too late to run.</p>
<p>The woman disappeared within a shimmering distortion. A loud crack filled the tent, drawing every eye to them and causing Min Li to gasp.</p>
<p>The woman had appeared behind him, her knife shimmering with green glass wrapped about it. Yet her strike, aimed precisely at the back of his neck, struck a crystal dome that had folded around both Stan and Min Li. The knife shattered, filling the tent with the sound and infecting the crystal with a green tint radiating outward from the impact.</p>
<p>Stan purged the green from his crystal, stabilizing it back into a clear, almost invisible dome. He turned to face his attacker. The Inquisitor gave Stan a dry smile, then pressed her shoulder into the dome. Green once again infected the crystal, radiating outward from the woman's shoulder and deepening in saturation far too quickly for his comfort.</p>
<p>It was not possible to overstate just how much he hated those jackets.</p>
<p>"You're a shaper?" Min Li asked in a confused tone.</p>
<p>"Not the time," he replied through gritted teeth.</p>
<p>The other Inquisitor arrived to press in from the other side. The entire dome glimmered green except for where their shoulders pressed into blue as the integrity deteriorated further.</p>
<p>"Dammit." He had only seconds before his surface collapsed.</p>
<p>So he collapsed it himself. The Inquisitors stumbled forward as the dome unravelled into strips of dissolving glass, right into two smaller spheres he thrust out just above eye level.</p>
<p>Their heads snapped back, and both Inquisitors collapsed, unconscious.</p>
<p>"Did you just—"</p>
<p>"They're still alive," Stan said, annoyed, then mumbled under his breath, "this time...I think."</p>
<p>Not that he intended to hang around and find out.</p>
<p>Min Li narrowed her eyes at him, which he studiously ignored. Over a dozen wide-eyed performers stared at him with expressions ranging from awe to outright horror. The pair of Royals had paused, looking uncertain between him and Min Li.</p>
<p>He turned to her. "I believe this is my cue for a timely—"</p>
<p>"I'm coming."</p>
<p>"Are you insane?" he almost shouted. "Inquisitors don't stop, ever."</p>
<p>"I'm coming," she repeated, then glanced at the Royals. "Better than the alternative."</p>
<p>"...alright, fine, crazy woman. Follow me."</p>
<p>He stomped his way toward the back of the tent without checking to see if she would follow. Blades of crystal formed before him. He sent them out to slice open a hole large enough for them to walk through. As the blades dissolved, a half dome of crystal folded over their heads. Rain pattered lightly on it.</p>
<p>His secret was out now; might as well be dry. Or most of him, anyway. Mud had already pressed in between his toes unpleasantly.</p>
<p>Forsaken gods but he could have used a little warning, if only to don a proper pair of boots.</p>
<p>They made it about a dozen paces before a shout behind them pierced the rain.</p>
<p>"Min Li Ch—"</p>
<p>"<em>No!</em>" she shouted as she spun, "I will not go back. You tell him I will <em>never</em> go back."</p>
<p>"And he will never stop, Min Li," the man replied in a tired voice. "You know this."</p>
<p>"I will never go back," she repeated, threading her arm through Stan's and drawing him close.</p>
<p>"Uh...?"</p>
<p>The man sneered at her, or him. It was hard to tell.</p>
<p>"Deal with them," she said in a flat tone.</p>
<p>"Deal? I am not your personal—"</p>
<p>"Just do it, or do you want them showing your Inquisitor friends exactly where we've gone?"</p>
<p>Stan rolled his eyes, but still formed a pair of crystal spheres, virtually invisible in the rain. They shot out toward the pair of Royals, glinting green then blue as they passed beyond his range and began to deteriorate.</p>
<p>The Royals saw it coming and tried to dodge, but it was far too late. Even as deteriorated glass, both balls struck hard enough that the sound made Stan flinch.</p>
<p>"Gotta figure out a better way to do that," he half mumbled to himself, hoping that crack he'd heard wasn't their skulls actually breaking.</p>
<p>Min Li quickly untangled her arm and levelled at him a strange look, like someone trying to figure a particularly difficult puzzle. Or maybe a cat trying to figure out how to pounce on a tasty morsel that just happened to have legs.</p>
<p>With that thought, he stared at the man's legs. Or rather, his feet.</p>
<p>"Where are you going?"</p>
<p>But Stan was already jogging toward the pair of men he'd just knocked unconscious. He knelt, first checking to make sure they were still alive, then...robbing them. Not everything of course—this wasn't about greed—and he didn't leave them naked or anything so crude. But both would wake up a just a little lighter, missing their cloak, money clip, and boots.</p>
<p>When he turned back, all his newly acquired contraband placed in a crystal box floating chest level, he found Min Li glaring at him a flat expression that promised murder.</p>
<p>"...oh."</p>
<p>He immediately formed a new umbrella of blue glass over her head, but the damage was done. Her hair had plastered to hear head and face, and her leotard had turned a full shade darker. Rain water dripped from her nose.</p>
<p>"If you're done pilfering the defenseless, perhaps we should leave before the Inquisitors wake up?"</p>
<p>Blue glass shifted to greens, lightening until it was as crystal clear as he approached. He dissolved it and expanded his personal umbrella over the both of them.</p>
<p>"Please tell me you have some sort of plan," Min Li asked.</p>
<p>He pulled out a cloak and handed it to her. She took it, but hesitated, something like disgust flashing across her face. Practicality won out and she donned the cloak.</p>
<p>"For Inquisitors?" He shook his head. "There is ever only one plan for them."</p>
<p>He threw the second cloak over his shoulders and trudged barefoot toward the tree line against which the troupe had set up. Hidden within the canopy shadows, he turned back to stare at yet another home lost.</p>
<p>Flashes of movement could be seen through the hole he'd carved in the tent, but nothing of Inquisitors yet. It wouldn't be long; they'd wasted too much time.</p>
<p>But this time it was 'they', and not him alone.</p>
<p>He wasn't sure how to feel about that.</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>apoetsanon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Run]]></title>
        <id>Volume_1.c02-Stan-Run</id>
        <link href="http://localhost:3000/chapters/Volume_1.c02-Stan-Run"/>
        <updated>2022-12-26T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Light folded itself into a crystal bowl. Of course, the bowl was made neither of crystal nor light, but graescent forces locked into a stable resonance. Those forces bent the light and reflected it rather like glass, or crystal, thus earning its name.</p>
<p>"I knew a shaper once," Min Li said as she dipped her feet into the water of a stream they'd found. "She was quite accomplished for her age. In her thirties, I think."</p>
<p>He sent the bowl down and brought up water. He dumped it over his feet all at once. Runnels of mud dripped down the stone he sat on, but not nearly enough to reveal actual feet beneath the muck caked to them.</p>
<p>"She'd learned three shapes in less than fifteen years. They named her a prodigy and called her a national asset."</p>
<p>The bowl expanded and then elongated on one side to form a spout. He sent it back down into the water and brought up considerably more water. He carefully poured it over a foot, wriggling his toes while rubbing his feet of the mud.</p>
<p>"She explained to me how difficult it was to shape. It took her years learning how to control her graescence well enough to form it into even the most basic shape. A single edge of light-blue glass, sharp enough to cut most anything."</p>
<p>He sent the bowl for water a third time and cleansed his other foot.</p>
<p>"I asked her if she could do more than one at a time. She laughed at me and said such things were all but impossible. She likened it to solving multiple advanced equations in your head all at once."</p>
<p>Stan blinked as a thought occurred to him. The rain had stopped over an hour ago, leaving a pleasant scattering of clouds and sun dappling the forest. He glanced up at the crystal umbrella he'd forgotten was there. It dissolved, seeming to fray at the edges first, and then unravel into strips that floated for a brief moment before disappearing in a riot of refracted color.</p>
<p>Crystal was quite beautiful when it unravelled in the light.</p>
<p>"You done?" He turned to her.</p>
<p>"Hmm." She pulled her feet from the stream and shook off the water.</p>
<p>"Good. We should go. The Inquisitors won't be far behind."</p>
<p>He split in half the crystal box holding his acquired shoes and sent the smaller pair of shoes to rest on the stone next to her. The box dissolved, and she took the shoes.</p>
<p>"They're probably too big," he said, "but better than nothing."</p>
<p>He shoved his feet into the larger pair and then stomped around a little to get used to them. After he was satisfied he wouldn't get too many blisters, he gestured at her to come over.</p>
<p>"This part'll be tricky."</p>
<p>She jumped up to the larger boulder he was standing on and gave him a dubious look. Crystal formed from the top of the stone and stretched until it met another boulder a short ways up stream. A bridge, and not a simple pane of crystal either. He'd arced the surface and formed a complex network of support structures underneath it.</p>
<p>Min Li screwed up her face. "We're <em>walking</em> on it?"</p>
<p>"Not like that we aren't. Hold on."</p>
<p>He focused on the feeling of the crystal, like a smooth texture in his mind, and willed a very specific kind of dissonance into it. The crystal shimmered orange.</p>
<p>"Citrine glass?" Min Li asked, perplexed. "I wasn't aware such a thing existed."</p>
<p>"Citrine? Huh, I like it." He stepped on the bridge and quickly walked to the other side.</p>
<p>She knelt and placed a hand flat on the glass. "It tingles."</p>
<p>"Yes, from the dissonance. Creates friction so we don't slide all over the place. Are you coming? I'd rather not repeat our encounter with our friends in black."</p>
<p>She stood and followed reluctantly, stepping lightly and eyeing the water as though she expected to be dumped into it at any moment.</p>
<p>He let the bridge dissolve and immediately formed another mildly arcing to a set of rocks he judged sturdy enough. In this way, they walked up river, bridging between boulder and rocks or downed trees, anything he could anchor to that wouldn't give away their presence. After some time, he found a perfect tree for the next stage of their journey.</p>
<p>"No, absolutely not." Min Li stared at a staircase of citrine glass leading away from the stream and up to a low hung tree branch.</p>
<p>"I've found trackers don't tend to look up much."</p>
<p>He climbed the staircase and gestured for her to follow.</p>
<p>"There has to be a better way," she said, shaking her head.</p>
<p>"Come or don't, but I'm not waiting around."</p>
<p>She bit her lip, looking deeply conflicted. She stepped tentative on the staircase. Then another and another, slowly growing her confidence. She placed a hand on the tree trunk and let out a slow breath he only now realized she'd been holding the entire ascent.</p>
<p>He formed a new set of stairs to another tree and walked up it, allowing the first staircase to dissolve. Min Li, stranded with only one direction to go, followed reluctantly. She kept glancing at the brush below her, which irritated him to no end. He wasn't going to drop her, dammit.</p>
<p>Once they were high enough, he formed simple bridges, allowing them to walk high above a thick undergrowth. Despite the effort of forming so much crystal, he found his shoulders relaxing the further they walked from their pursuers.</p>
<p>Min Li was not relaxed, at all. She walked carefully, uncertain, her eyes darting between the trees and him. He knew what she was thinking. Just one lapse of concentration, just one little mistake in the advanced calculus required to form such shapes, and he would dump both of them over fifty paces into the thick underbrush below.</p>
<p>"Was she happy?" Stan asked, his pace leisurely now that they'd gained some distance. "Your shaper friend?"</p>
<p>Min Li startled. "I...I would imagine so, though we were never friends."</p>
<p>"Why?"</p>
<p>"...why what?"</p>
<p>"Why do you think she was happy?"</p>
<p>Min Li snorted. "Money? Respect? She's probably one of the highest paid people in the province."</p>
<p>"So money is what it takes to be happy?"</p>
<p>"No, of course not." She frowned. "It does help though."</p>
<p>"What did she do?"</p>
<p>"Guarded the Matron."</p>
<p>"Ah, a guard." He couldn't quite keep the distaste from his tone.</p>
<p>"It's an honored position," Min Li bristled, "that raised her whole family."</p>
<p>"Of course it did."</p>
<p>She huffed, looking as though she wanted to argue. She closed her mouth instead, glancing nervously at the bridge of citrine they stood on.</p>
<p>"I'm not going to drop you, dammit," he growled, picking up his pace. "Come on."</p>
<p>They walked an hour before Stan began to feel the strain of making so much glass. Crystal was easier for him, a small bit of irony that to create imperfection required so much more work, the exact opposite of every other shaper in existence. He had no doubt Min Li spoke truth about her shaper friend, who'd devoted her life to approaching a perfection he couldn't help but create naturally.</p>
<p>Min Li visibly relaxed when her feet touched the ground. He scowled at her. They'd literally been walking among the tree tops, a thing he'd once thought would be a great way to woo a woman. Instead, he got Min Li.</p>
<p>"Why are you even here?"</p>
<p>"Which way now?" she asked, ignoring his question as she looked around the small glade they'd stepped into.</p>
<p>Several paths led deeper into the forest. Stan seemed to consider them for a few moments, then chose one at random. The path was more of a suggestion of the imagination than any real trail. He formed crystal walls to carefully press back the foliage, while trying to avoid breaking it. It would have been far easier to cut a path, but he was still wary about leaving a trail.</p>
<p>They walked until, apparently, Min Li couldn't take it anymore.</p>
<p>"<em>Where</em> are we going?" she asked in an accusatory tone he was beginning to hate.</p>
<p>He paused, then point down the not-trail. "That way."</p>
<p>"No," she huffed, "I mean what's our destination. I cannot think of a single city, town, or village in this direction."</p>
<p>"This way," he replied without pausing.</p>
<p>She growled something incomprehensible under her breath and stomped after him. Another hour passed trudging through the undergrowth before they reach another glade. This one was long with trees lined up on either side, hinting at something like order or design that wasn't actually there.</p>
<p>They followed it for a while before Stan abruptly veered off to push through undergrowth again. It took a few seconds to realize Min Li was no longer following him.</p>
<p>He turned around and found her still standing in the glade, looking at him with an incredulous expression.</p>
<p>"You're lost," she accused him.</p>
<p>"Yep." He blinked, then turned and continued to press through the forest.</p>
<p>"No no no no no." She rushed to him and grabbed his arm, spinning him about. "<em>No!</em> Why...why would you get us lost? In a forest of all places? Where are we going to sleep?"</p>
<p>He glanced at a sun who's color had just begun to deepen into evening.</p>
<p>"The ground, probably."</p>
<p>Her face fell. "Noooo..."</p>
<p>He began walking again, leaving her to wallow in distress. He'd only taken a few steps before she caught up to him again.</p>
<p>"But why? Why would you do this?" 'To me,' seemed to be the implication.</p>
<p>He shrugged. "Cause they won't expect it. Or, even if they do, it's really hard to find a person lost in a forest."</p>
<p>"No, that's not...no, just no. We need to find a village or a town or <em>something</em>."</p>
<p>"And you don't think they'll anticipate that?"</p>
<p>"So we be careful."</p>
<p>"There is no careful, Min Li. It's not just two people we have to avoid. Or four, I guess, with whoever's after you. It's their entire network. And let me tell you, Inquisitors have a very, very thorough network."</p>
<p>"But—"</p>
<p>"The <em>only</em> thing we can do is avoid their network," he gestured around, "until we can go where they aren't looking."</p>
<p>"...where is that?"</p>
<p>"Far, like weeks far."</p>
<p>Min Li pressed her face into her hands and moaned.</p>
<p>"How are we going to eat?" she asked through her fingers.</p>
<p>"Oh, there's plenty to eat in a forest."</p>
<p>"No—"</p>
<p>"You say that a lot."</p>
<p>"—I cannot eat only meat for weeks on end."</p>
<p>"...sorry?" His brow creased. "I don't know what you want from me, Min Li. I have Inquisitors after me, <em>Inquisitors</em>."</p>
<p>"You seemed to handle them easily enough. I've never heard of anyone incapacitating Inquisitors quite so quickly as you."</p>
<p>"And then what? I can handle two, sure. Four? Probably. But six, eight, <em>ten</em>? I don't want to escalate things, Min. I want them to leave me alone."</p>
<p>He spun on heel and stomped into brush, crystal pushing it back as he progressed.</p>
<p>"Li," she spoke quietly to his back. "My name is Min <em>Li</em>."</p>
<p>He continued for only a few minutes before stopping again and turning back to her, fuming.</p>
<p>"Why are you following me, anyway? You clearly know where the nearest village is or whatever. Go there and sleep in a bed and eat...not meat, or whatever. And you know what, <em>here</em>."</p>
<p>He reached over to the money folds he'd secured with a small strip of crystal, crystal that had been floating so close to his hip she hadn't realized it wasn't attached.</p>
<p>He thrust the money at her.</p>
<p>She glanced at it contemptuously. "Oh yes, I'm sure you'd love that. I'd make a perfect decoy for the Inquisitors to follow."</p>
<p>"That's not what I—"</p>
<p>"Why are they after you, Stan Li? I get that you're gifted—"</p>
<p>"Don't call me that," he growled.</p>
<p>She rolled her eyes. "Inquisitors don't go after the gifted, Stan <em>Li</em>, they go after..." Her faced paled.</p>
<p>His face blanched as a deadly silence was born between them.</p>
<p>"I am not one of them," he said in a thin tone filled with too much fear and pain. She did not find it convincing.</p>
<p>He turned from her and pushed through brush again, his body leaning forward in effort as the crystal pressed back the vegetation that would normally make passage all but impossible. More impressive, he wasn't forming solid walls of crystal. They undulated around the foliage, pressing each branch back individually just enough that they wouldn't break.</p>
<p>He wasn't perfect, and occasionally branches did break. Yet the display demonstrated a proficiency that was all but impossible. Min Li knew there were gifted that could modify the shape of their glass, but it took decades of practice to manage the simplest changes and, generally, the practice was considered academic and impractical. Better to learn well simple shapes that could be called into existence easily.</p>
<p>Of course, shapers only ever made glass too, and Stan created crystal, a feat most considered theoretical.</p>
<p>"Were you tested?" she asked after a few minutes.</p>
<p>His body tensed, but he didn't stop. "I've never destroyed a town, or a village, or even a building," he said defensively. "I've never blown up or anything like what they say godlings do."</p>
<p>"Yeah," she said slowly, "but were you tested?"</p>
<p>He said nothing, which was answer enough. She matched his silence. He could feel her uncertainty, her suspicion, her accusation in the words she didn't speak. He was a walking bomb and anything could set him off. At any moment he could destroy everything because that's what godlings did and that's why Inquisitors hunted them.</p>
<p>He didn't even blame them for it. He couldn't. Godlings were a blight. They needed to be hunted down and destroyed before they could threaten all of society.</p>
<p>He just...didn't want to die. He was scared, and the shame ate him from the inside out, a slow burning cancer that destroyed every home he tried to make.</p>
<p>The sun dipped into the horizon, hidden beyond their sight yet tainting the sky's blues with colors his citrine bridges could disappear into. He stopped at a small clearing, barely even a glade at less than ten paces in size.</p>
<p>Min Li watched expressionless as he put on a display that would make the most accomplished shapers green with envy, all to collect sticks into piles. It took her too long to realize what he intended.</p>
<p>"Won't the smoke give us away?"</p>
<p>"Not if there's no smoke."</p>
<p>Her face turned perplexed as he formed a tall, narrow cylinder of crystal with vents along the bottom. He packed it vertically with the smallest of the sticks he'd gathered. He formed a sliver of crystal above, took a deep breath, and drove the dissonance into gold.</p>
<p>Her brow pinched. "Yellow glass now!?"</p>
<p>"Don't touch it," he replied in a strained voice. "It's very abrasive."</p>
<p>He thrust the glass into sticks. After a few seconds, a thin line of smoke threaded its way out of the pile. He maintained the yellow even as sweat began to bead on his forehead. Finally, he saw the flicker of a flame. He let the sliver of glass dissolve, which it did quite readily.</p>
<p>"I don't understand. How can glass make fire?"</p>
<p>"Friction," he replied with a sigh, wiping his brow, "a whole lot of friction."</p>
<p>She cocked her head at him. "And that was hard?"</p>
<p>He nodded. "Yellow's not stable. Takes a lot to keep it formed."</p>
<p>"But crystal, the same crystal everyone says is impossible to make, <em>that's</em> easy?"</p>
<p>He snorted. "Very. It's stable. Once it's formed, it takes almost nothing to keep it there."</p>
<p>She blinked slowly at him. "That's not how it's supposed to work."</p>
<p>He shrugged, then sat down in the dirt to watch the flames grow. He kept careful eye on the smoke, ready to close off the crystal if his fire did produce too much smoke. So far, the forest canopy dispersed the little smoke drifting through the leaves.</p>
<p>"I've never talked to another shaper before, but I think...I think it does work that way. I'm just coming at it from the other direction."</p>
<p>She sat down next to him. "What do you mean?"</p>
<p>He turned a hand over and formed a crystal ball above it.</p>
<p>"This? This took nothing to make. No no, I mean it," he said, laughing at her expression, "feeding a light takes way more graescence than forming this. The graescence this takes is so little I can't feel it leaving me at all."</p>
<p>He concentrated a moment and the crystal turned into a light green glass.</p>
<p>"This is...well, I can feel it, but it's more like holding a marble in your hand. You know the weight is there, but you can ignore it."</p>
<p>He took a breath and focused again, turning the light green glass into a light blue.</p>
<p>"This is hard, like holding a large dog with one hand. I can do it, but it's a lot of effort."</p>
<p>He let the glass dissolve.</p>
<p>"And violet?" she asked.</p>
<p>He shook his head. "I can't really make violet. It's just too much. My shapes sometimes turn violet if I send them out of my range, but they dissolve quickly. I can't support them; they take too much graescence."</p>
<p>Min Li fell silent, her brow furrowed in thought. The fire had grown large enough that Stan felt comfortable adding to it. He expanded the cylinder, allowing the half-burnt twigs to drop to the bottom. He then inserted new, larger twigs to the mix. It was a careful balance. Too big and the fire would burn dirty. Too small and it would burn too quickly. He carefully watched the smoke, making sure it wouldn't plume above the forest canopy.</p>
<p>"You realize this changes everything? If we could just teach people how to form crystal first..."</p>
<p>"We could what?" He turned to her. "Kill our enemies better? Easier? We could invade other provinces with impunity, maybe? Frozen hells, perhaps we could even challenge the Empire!"</p>
<p>"That's not what I mean."</p>
<p>"I know. But you can't deny it's what would happen."</p>
<p>She didn't deny it. She stared at the fire instead, watching it grow. Stan's construct was fascinating. The crystal made the fire look as though it were floating in air, which was halfway true. But she also watched a dried leaf flutter by one of the vents as it pulled in air to feed the fire.</p>
<p>Such innovation from pure imagination, formed into reality with no effort at all.</p>
<p>What <em>would</em> people do with that kind of power?</p>
<p>"I don't want to be a weapon," he said finally in a small voice. "I just want to..."</p>
<p>Make art. He wanted to dance and flip through the air, becoming a thing of beauty to enlighten others. And yes, he <em>wanted</em> to use his gift; he wanted to use it to show the world a different way, a better way. Yet he couldn't put the idea into words. He <em>wouldn't</em>.</p>
<p>"You're delusional," she said as a matter of fact.</p>
<p>He hated her for those words, but he nodded anyway. Some dreams were too fragile to speak out loud.</p>
]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>apoetsanon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>